So, Father, once more
Earthmen have invaded our space.
看，父亲，地球人又一次入侵了我们的空间
You will address the Emperor
in a proper manner.
你得先用得体的方式先皇帝致礼
Your pardon.
请您谅解
May I have permission to address the Emperor?
我可以向皇帝致礼吗？
My life at your command.
我听候您的差遣
One day, my Son, you will inherit this throne.
某一天，儿子，你会继承这个宝座
Then you will realise the importance of due formality.
那时你就会明白仪式感的重要性
Now, what do you wish to say?
现在看看，你想要说些什么？
Surely, now you will declare war
upon the Earthmen?
当然。现在你们要向地球人宣战了吗？
Let me lead your battle fleets
to crush their...
让我带领你的战斗舰队去碾压他们的...
They too, have battle fleets, my Son.
他们一样，也有战斗舰队，孩子
Such a war could well bring down both empires.
这样的战争很可能把这两个帝国都摧毁
Not if we strike first,
then we shall be the victors!
如果我们先行出击就不会，我们将会是胜利者！
In such a war, there are no victors.
在这样的战争中, 没有胜利者
The nobles of the court are demanding action.
王廷上的贵族们都要求采取行动
They fear for the honour of Draconia.
他们担心龙帝国的荣誉
I am the emperor!
The honour of Draconia is vested in me.
我是皇帝，龙帝国的荣誉在我这里
The throne depends upon
the great families for support.
皇位也依赖于各大家族的支持
Emperors have been deposed before now.
以前也有皇帝被废掉
An emperor who does not rule
deposes himself!
一个不统治的皇帝就会被遗弃!
Then what will you do, Father?
那你决定怎么做，父亲？
I shall question these Earthmen myself.
我将亲自找这些地球人问话
I have already sent for them.
我已经让人去带他们过来了
Why waste time listening to their lies?
为什么要浪费时间听他们的谎言呢？
Majesty, I bring the prisoners.
陛下，我把囚犯带过来了
May I have permission to address the Emperor?
允许我向皇帝致礼吗？
Wait!
等一下！
This is an insult!
这是种侮辱！
My life at your command, sire.
我听候您的差遣，陛下
How dare you address the Emperor
你怎敢这样向皇帝致礼？
in a manner reserved for a noble of Draconia?
这是龙帝国贵族才可以使用的方式
Ah, but I am a noble of Draconia.
啊，但我是龙帝国贵族
The honour was conferred on me
by the 15th Emperor.
这项荣誉是第十五世皇帝授予我的
The 15th Emperor reigned 500 years ago.
第十五世皇帝是500年前了
(LAUGHING)
Your Majesty, do not be taken
in by this ridiculous story...
陛下，别被这种荒谬的故事给诓进去了
Be silent!
安静！
There is a legend among our people
我们的人当中的确有个传说
of a man who assisted the 15th Emperor
at a time of great trouble
说有个人在十五世皇帝非常困难的时期帮了大忙
when we were almost overwhelmed
by a great plague from outer space.
当时我们被外太空来的一种厉害的瘟疫害得不轻
But you could not be that man.
No Earthman lives so long.
但你不可能是那个人。没有哪个地球人能活那么久
Your Majesty, this man that you speak of,
陛下，你所说的这个人
was he not known as the Doctor?
是不是都叫他博士？
And did he not come to this planet
in a spaceship called the TARDIS?
而且他是乘坐一个叫做 TARDIS 的飞船来到这个星球的？
He did.
是的
Well, I am that man, sire.
对了，我就是那个人，陛下
And I come from a race of people
that live far longer than any Earthman.
我来自另外一个种族，我们比地球人寿命长得多
Even if I accept your claim,
you have broken our law.
即使我接受你宣称的这个身份，你也触犯了法律
Why did you violate Draconian space?
你为什么要侵犯龙帝国边界？
Your Majesty, this man was, and still is, my prisoner.
陛下，这个人本来是我的囚犯，现在也还是
It is true, Your Majesty.
这是真的，陛下
I did come here as a prisoner,
but I came willingly,
我的确是以囚犯身份来到这里的，但愿意过来
in order to inform you that
this man is plotting a war
只是为了告诉你们，这个人试图挑起一场战争
between Earth and Draconia!
以让地球和龙帝国两败俱伤！
All Earthmen are determined upon war.
所有地球人都铁了心要一场战争
Ah, but the Master is not an Earthman.
是，但这位法师不是地球人
I'm sorry to have to admit it,
but he's a renegade of my own race
我不得不惭愧地承认，他是我那个种族中的败类
and he's using creatures called Ogrons
他利用了一种叫做 Ogrons 的生物
to attack your spaceships and those of the Earthmen.
攻击了你们和那些地球人的飞船
The Earthmen who attacked our spaceships,
那些袭击过我们的地球人
they have been seen many times.
之前也被看到过很多次
I'm sorry, but there you are in error, sir.
抱歉，你们搞错了，阁下
Your people have seen Ogrons,
你们的人看见的是 Ogrons
but they appear to them as Earthmen
because of a hypnotic device.
但你们以为你们看见的是地球人，这都是因为一种致幻装置
It's true, Your Majesty.
这是真的，陛下
When the Ogrons attacked the Earth ships,
当 Ogrons 攻击地球飞船的时候
the Earthmen saw them as Draconians.
地球人看他们就是龙族人
Silence! Females are not permitted
to speak in the presence of the Emperor.
安静！女人不允许在皇帝面前说话
Your Majesty, do not be deceived
by the pathetic ravings
陛下, 不要被这些可悲的胡言乱语欺骗了
of two criminals trying to evade justice.
这两个罪犯只是试图逃避法律制裁
If what you say is true, it would explain much.
如果你说的是真的，那很多东西就解释得通了
We lived at peace with the Earthmen
for many years,
我们跟地球人和平共处了这么多年
then suddenly they began to raid our spaceships.
他们突然间就开始攻击我们的飞船了
When we protested, they said that we were attacking them.
我们提出抗议的时候，他们又说是我们在攻击他们
In order to cover up their own attacks!
他们是在掩盖他们自己的攻击行为！
This is simply a plot of the Earthmen
to lull us into false security.
这只是地球人的阴谋, 让我们陷入虚假的安全
Speak!
说！
Your Majesty, a spaceship from Earth
陛下，地球来了一艘飞船
seeks permission to land in the palace spaceport.
请求降落在皇家空港
They say they're on a special mission
from the President of Earth.
他们说他们在执行地球总统授命的一项特殊任务
This is a trick! You must not allow them to land!
这是个骗局！你不能让他们着陆！
We are not yet at war with Earth.
我们跟地球还没开战
I shall hear what their president has to say.
我要听听他们的总统有什么可说的
I give my permission.
我给他们许可
Your Majesty.
陛下
A wise decision, Your Majesty.
一个明智的决定，陛下
For only by Earth and Draconia
working together
只有地球和龙帝国一起努力
can we hope to arrive at the truth.
我们才有期望得到真相
I, too, welcome your wisdom,
Your Majesty.
我赞同你智慧的决策，陛下
Nobody could be more devoted
to the cause of peace than I.
没有人比我更热衷于和平事业
As a commissioner of Earth's
Interplanetary Police,
作为地球的星际警局专员
I have devoted my life to the cause of law and order.
我把我的一生都献给了法律和秩序事业
And law and order can only exist
in a time of peace.
而法律和秩序只能在和平的时代存在
You feeling all right, old chap?
你感觉还好吗, 老伙计？
Only during a period of social stability,
只有在社会稳定时期，
can society adequately deal with criminals
社会才能有力打击罪犯
such as this man and this unfortunate girl.
就像这个人和这个不幸女孩儿这样的罪犯
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Doctor, listen! That sound!
博士，听！那个声音！
PRINCE: Silence, female!
安静，女人！
Quiet!
安静！
It's the same noise that I heard on the cargo ship.
这和我在货船上听到的声音是一样的
Doctor, it's the Ogrons!
博士，是 Ogrons！
Your Majesty, I beg of you to be cautious.
陛下，我请求你小心行事
Something is seriously wrong here.
This ship that has just landed,
这里有些事非常不对劲。刚刚降落的那艘飞船，
I beg you, place it under guard immediately.
我请求你，把它纳入警戒控制之内
Your Majesty, please?
陛下，可以吗？
DRACONIAN: (SHOUTING) Earthmen!
地球人！
MASTER: Seize them, fool!
抓住它们，笨蛋！
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ah, you idiots! Back to the ship, all of you!
啊，这群笨蛋！回到船上去吧，你们全部！
Come on, back to the ship!
快点，回到船上去！
Now will you believe
in the treachery of the Earthmen?
现在你相信地球人会背信弃义吧？
Your Majesty, look down here
and tell me, what do you see?
陛下，往下看看，告诉我，你看到的是什么？
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
I see one of your Earth soldiers
我看到了一个你们的地球士兵
who attacked my palace and killed my people.
是他攻击我皇宫、杀我族人
Jo? Jo, can you still hear that sound?
Jo? 你还能听到那声音吗？
(HYPNOTIC PULSE FADING)
Yes, it's fading. It's almost gone.
是的，不过小了，基本听不到了
Your Majesty, I beg of you, please.
Look again.
陛下，我请求你，再看一眼
Why do we delay? Destroy him!
还耽搁什么？消灭他！
Wait!
等等！
He has spoken the truth.
他说的是实情
Great, lumbering idiots!
很好，蠢笨的家伙！
Now you tell me that you've left
one of your fellows in the palace!
现在你跟说你把一个家伙留在皇宫里了!
Do you realise what this means?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
As soon as the effect
of the hypno-sound wears off,
一旦催眠声音的效果消失了
the Draconians will know
who it really was who attacked them.
龙族人就会知道真正是谁攻击了他们
You've ruined everything!
你们坏了所有的事！
What shall we do now?
我们现在该怎么办？
Do? There's only one thing we can do.
办？只有一件事我们能办
Make sure that the Doctor and his evidence
确保博士和他的证据...
is never allowed to reach Earth.
绝对到不了地球！
Why does the Master want war
between Earth and Draconia?
为什么法师想要让地球和龙帝国之间发生战争？
Did you attack our spaceships
and those of the Earthmen?
是你攻击了我们的飞船吗？地球人的呢？
Oh, it's no good. We're not getting anywhere.
噢，这样没用。我们什么也问不出来
Let me take him for questioning.
He will answer to me.
让我把他带去问话吧，他会告诉我的
I shall use the mind probe.
我将使用思维探测器
You'd only be wasting your time.
你这只是在浪费时间
The Ogrons have got the finest
defence mechanism of all, stupidity.
They haven't got a mind
for you to probe.
Then remove him.
We will deal with him later.
Why did that sound make us see
this creature as a soldier from Earth?
为什么那个声音会让我们把这个生物看成是来自地球的士兵？
Because you're frightened of Earthmen.
因为你们害怕地球人
Draconians fear nothing, female.
龙族人什么也不怕，女人
Well, of course you do.
You fear them and they fear you.
得了，你们当然怕，你们怕他们，他们怕你们
That's why when Earthmen heard that sound, they saw Draconians.
这就是为什么当地球人听到这个声音时, 他们看到了龙族人
That is true.
说得没错
We do fear the Earthmen and they fear us.
我们害怕地球人，他们也怕我们
And fear breeds hatred, Your Majesty.
而恐惧滋生仇恨，陛下
Fear is the greatest enemy of them all, for fear leads us to war.
恐惧是最大的敌人，因为恐惧导致我们走向战争
We shall tell the Earthmen
what has happened here.
我们要告诉地球人这里发生了什么
They, too, must know the truth.
他们也得知道真相
They will not believe us.
他们不会相信我们的
The Prince is right, Your Majesty.
王子是对的，陛下
We must mount an expedition at once
and we must take the Ogron as evidence.
我们必须立即安排一支队伍, 而且必须带上食人魔作为证据
The empires are on the verge of war.
俩帝国正处于战争的边缘
A Draconian spaceship in Earth space
一艘龙帝国飞船进入地球空间，
could be destroyed before it reaches its destination.
还没到达目的地就可能被摧毁了
We could use the ship the Master brought us in.
我们可以用法师带我们来的那艘飞船
It's an Earth police spaceship.
那是一艘地球警局的飞船
Females are not permitted to speak...
女人不允许说话...
The female may speak.
这个女人可以说话
But...
但是...
We must respect the customs of our guests, strange though they may be.
我们必须尊重我们客人的习俗，不管它们看起来多么奇怪
The suggestion had merit.
这项建议值得采纳
Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢谢你，陛下
You too, will go on this mission.
你，也将参加这次任务
But it must be headed by a Draconian of noble rank.
但必须得有龙族爵位的人带队
I shall send my son.
我将送我的儿子去
Doctor, where are we?
博士，我们在哪儿？
We're just about to cross the frontier into Earth space.
我们就要跨越边界进入地球空间了
Ooh, that's good.
喔，太好了
Unless your Earth people destroy us.
咱们可别被你们地球人摧毁了
Well, this is an Earth police spaceship, you know, sir.
这可是一艘地球警局的飞船，你知道吧
Even if it is stolen.
即使它是偷来的
What is that?
那是什么？
DOCTOR: It looks like another spaceship.
看起来像是又一艘飞船
It appears to be following us.
它好像一直跟着我们
OGRON: Look!
看！
MASTER: Well, that must be them.
好了，那肯定是他们
DOCTOR: We should be picking them up
on the visual scanner now.
我们现在应该能在视频扫描仪上看到他们了
JO: It's an Ogron ship!
这是艘 Ogron 的船
Fire!
开火！
DOCTOR: Hang on. I think we're shaking them off.
把住。我想我们我们可以甩掉他们
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Doctor!
博士！
He's broken out! Get out, Jo!
他逃出来了。出去，Jo！
MASTER: We must have hit them.
They're losing speed.
我们肯定击中他们了，他们速度下来了
OGRON: Shall I fire again?
要我再次开火吗？
No, no, it might be possible
to take the Doctor alive after all.
不不，必须要能够生擒住博士
Muster a boarding party.
召集一个登机小队
Yes, Master.
好的，法师
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Right, there you are, my friend.
好了，乖乖的吧，朋友
Are you all right?
你没事吧
JO: Oh, no, you don't!
噢，不，你不能！
No, no!
不，不！
- No, let go of me!
- This way!
- 不，放开我！  - 这边！
JO: Let me go!
放开我！
We've been boarded! We need the blasters, come on!
有人登船了！我们需要枪，快来！
- The prisoner?
- Don't worry about him.
- 俘虏呢？  - 不用操心他了
He's no use to us at the moment.
现在这个时候他对我们没用了
JO: Let me go! No! Doctor!
放开我！不！博士！
DOCTOR: Get down!
OGRON: The enemy!
- 蹲下！ - 有敌人！
OGRON: Fool, go!
傻瓜，走！
JO: Help! Doctor!
OGRON: You come!
- 救命，博士！  - 你过来！
- You must come!
- No!
- 你必须过来！  - 不！
Look out! We must take the girl!
小心！我们必须带着这个女孩儿！
No!
不！
In here!
进来！
MASTER: Right. Unlock!
行了。断开！
CAPTAIN ON RADIO:
This is Earth battle cruiser X29.
这里是地球战斗巡航舰X29
Do you read me? Identify yourself.
你能听到吗？请表明你的身份
This is Earth battle cruiser X29.
这里是地球战斗巡航舰X29
Do you read me? Identify yourself.
你能听到吗？请表明你的身份
Hello, this is Earth police spaceship 2390,
你好，这是地球警用飞船2390
on a special mission to the President of Earth. Over.
正在执行一项特殊任务，飞往地球总统。结束
CAPTAIN: Identify the ship
that has just unlocked from you.
表明刚与你船断开的飞船身份
They refuse to answer our signals.
他们拒绝应答我们的问话
Look, it's of vital importance
注意，这是非常重要的：
that you pursue and capture
that ship immediately. Over.
你们应该立刻追上那艘飞船，抓获他们。结束
You are in possession
of a stolen police spaceship.
你们占有了一艘被偷走的警用飞船
You are under arrest.
Stand by to be boarded.
你们被捕了。我们即将登船，请准备
DOCTOR ON RADIO:
Look, you don't understand.
听着，你没有弄明白
The man who stole this ship
is escaping in that vessel.
偷了这艘船的人正在用那个船上逃走
CAPTAIN: You are under arrest.
你们被捕了
You'll be given the opportunity
of making a full statement.
你们有机会做完整的陈述
Do not offer any resistance.
Stand by to be boarded.
不要做任何抵抗，我们即将登船
DOCTOR: Oh, very well.
We're standing by.
哦，好吧，我们待命
(LAUGHING)
Poor Doctor. Enmeshed in the throes of bureaucracy.
可怜的博士，陷入官僚主义的痛苦之中
(LAUGHING)
It'll take him a long time
to talk himself out of that one.
可得要些时间他才能说明白，再脱开身
But he'll get to see the President,
eventually.
但他最终会去见到总统
She won't believe him.
总统不会相信他
Oh, yes, she will, when she sees the Ogron prisoner.
哦，会，她会的，只要看见 Ogron 俘虏就会了
He's our evidence.
他是我们的证据
Your evidence is standing
right behind you.
你的证据正站在你的后面呢
The Draconian Prince knows
the truth and he's with the Doctor.
龙族王子知道真相，他也跟博士在一起
My dear, Miss Grant, in the climate
of opinion that I have created,
我亲爱的 Grant 小姐，在我制造的舆论趋势下
do you think that any Earthman
你觉得任何地球人
is going to believe the word of a Draconian?
会相信一个龙族人的话么？
Your Highness, we've heard the Doctor's theory before.
殿下，我们之前已经听过这个博士的理论
And, with respect, there is still no concrete evidence.
而且，恕我直言，它并没有可靠证据支撑
I myself would like to believe you
but, as you can see,
我个人倒是想要相信你。但是，如你所见
I need proof to convince my people.
我需要证据去说服我的人
Then we must mount an expedition
to the planet of the Ogrons.
那我们必须安排一队人去 Ogrons 的星球
The proof we need is there, madam.
我们需要的证据在那里，夫人
With Earth on the brink of war,
how can we divert our forces
眼看地球处于战争边缘，我们怎么能转移我们的力量
into such a pointless expedition?
去搞这种无意义的远征呢？
My dear chap, I'm not asking for a battle fleet.
我亲爱的伙计，我不是要求派一支战斗舰队去
All I require is one small spaceship.
我所要的只是一艘小飞船
Well, Miss Grant, welcome to my humble abode.
好了，Grant 小姐，欢迎来到我简陋的土屋
I think you were better off in prison.
我觉得你在监狱里过得比这更好
Oh, temporary quarters, my dear.
噢，临时住所而已，亲爱的
I shall soon be changing them
for something better.
我很快就会将他们换成更好的
Oh, you'll soon be back in jail.
噢，对，你很快就会回到监狱了
When the truth gets out,
等真相一出来
Earth and Draconia will combine
their forces to attack you.
地球和龙族就会联合起来对付你
I don't think so. There's too much distrust between them.
我不觉得。他们之间有太多的不信任
The Doctor will find you, eventually.
博士最终会找到你
Ah, there I agree with you. He must find me.
啊，这我倒是同意你的说法，他必须找到我
Not only to rescue you,
不仅是要来救你
but also to be reunited with his beloved TARDIS.
还要跟他所爱的 TARDIS 会合